

RF System Specialist

roonlafisa@gmail.com | +1-905-783-3906 | https://roonlafisa.github.io

Toronto, Canada (Canadian Citizen)

Summary

I have been working in the space Industry for over five years with a thirst to learn new things every day. I have 8 years of RF system design experience for IoT, Cubesats, and Rocket. More recently, I have led the design and development of a full-stack (design to assembly) avionics system for an orbital-scale rocket.

Skills

System design: End-to-end RF component and subsystem, Avionics hardware component and subsystem, PCB design, JIRA.

RF design: RF system, Link budgets, Ground station, Antenna design, Filter design.

RF hardware: RFD900x, Iridium, Globalstar, Quasonix, Safran, CCSDS Receivers, Ublox GPS, JAVAD GPS, LimeSDR, Transponder.

RF software: CST, HFSS, ADS, MATLAB tools, Custom scripts/simulation.

Standards: IPC-620D (Workmanship), AS50881G (Wiring), MIL-810 (Environmental test).

Electronics: ESP32, STM32, IMU, i2C, CAN, RS-232, Jetson TX2i.

Programming: Python, C, MATLAB, Linux.

PCB: LT Spice, CircuitStudio, Altium, Circuit Studio, Ki-CAD.

CAD: Solidworks, Solidworks electrical.

Lab: Oscilloscope, Signal generator, Electrical load, Network Analyzer, Logic analyzer, SMD soldering.

Professional History

Senior RF Specialist - SpaceRyde, Toronto ON

Sept 2021 - Present

- · Designed and implemented manufacturing of the **rocket avionics system** including flight computers, GNC, power management, data networking, RF communications on subsystem and component levels.
- · Architected and verified the **end-to-end RF system** to receive rocket telemetry using legacy COTS design.
- · Interfaced with regulatory authority (ISED) regarding radio licensing for rocket telemetry spectrum licensing.
- \cdot Designed, created, assembled, and tested **4-layer PCBs** which incorporates embedded MCU, ADC, Radio interfacing, and power management system.
- · CAD-modeled and assembled avionics flight components, wires, and connectors inside flight enclosures.
- · Spearheaded the development of **test procedures and campaigns** for the validation of avionics components.
- · Produced systems requirements and derived requirements for developing avionics components.

Intermediate RF Engineer - SMT Research, Vancouver BC

April 2020 - Aug 2021

- · Designed and implemented a battery-less **RF power harvesting** wireless system for structural monitoring.
- · Pioneered custom **RFID passive sensor** tags for remote data logging and pinpointing hidden sensor locations.
- · Installed sensors and DAQs in active construction sites and provided technical support to installation technicians.

RF Engineering Consultant - Direct Kinetic Solutions, Texas (Remote)

July 2017 - May 2019

· Produced custom **Cubesat EPS and RF system** concepts for clients and DOD grant applications.

Lead RF Engineer - Helios Wire, Vancouver BC

July 2017 - May 2019

- · Custom designed and successfully deployed **C-, X- and S-Band antennas** for CubeSat TT&C communication.
- · Conceptualized and modeled an iot gateway to interface between Cubesat in space and IoT tags in the ground.

Educational History

MASc in EE - University of British Columbia, Kelowna BC

Sept 2014 - Oct 2016

· Master Thesis: "A broadband fixed-beam leaky-wave antenna based on transformation electromagnetics."

BSc in EEE - Islamic University of Technology

Jan 2010 - Oct 2013

· Activities: Led the university robotics team during the NASA Lunabotics Annual Competition 2013.